MAKI HIROSE

Portfolio: makicoding.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/makihirose</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/makicoding</u> Contact: <u>maki@makicoding.com</u> | 347-615-1458 | New York, NY 11415

SUMMARY

Product Designer with coding skills, over ten years of visual experience in the Commercial Photography Industry and a Certified Scrum Master. Project leader and expert at color, composition and paying close attention to detail. Bilingual in English and Japanese.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

UX/UI: Project Management, Market Research, User Research, Contextual Inquiry, User Interviewing, Affinity Mapping, User Persona, Card Sorting, Information Architecture, User Flow, Sketching, Wireframing, Wireflow, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Heuristic Evaluation, Prototyping, Responsive Web Design.

<u>Web Development:</u> React, JavaScript, CSS, JSX, HTML5, Bootstrap, jQuery, RESTful API, AJAX, AXIOS, JSON, Firebase, Node, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, ORM, Handlebars, Heroku, JawsDB, mLab, Chrome DevTools, Git, GitHub, Agile, Scrum.

<u>Software:</u> Visual Studio Code, InVision, Sketch, Figma, XD, Photoshop, Lightroom, Bridge, After Effects, Premiere, Audition, Capture One, Photo Mechanic, Final Cut Pro, Logic Pro, Pro Tools, Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Google Slides, Command Line.

EXPERIENCE

Product Designer - Freelance - New York, NY

2012-Present

Conducted market research, user research, reported insights to the team, discussed and ideated app designs using Sketch, performed usability testing using InVision, iterated designs and executed visual design. Solicited feedback from client. Coded app using React, vanilla JavaScript, MongoDB, MySQL and various other technologies. Prepared Google Slides presentations and demonstrated app iterations to client.

• Notable Clients: Maybelline, Smirnoff, Tanqueray Gin, Grind Espresso Spirit, Blade & Bow and more.

Advertising Photographer - MAKIDIGITAL LLC - New York, NY

2012-2019

Founded and operated business, including key decision-making for B2B and B2C marketing, social media, photography and video shoots. Headed teams on large scale Advertising Photoshoots, shooting images for both web apps and print, working alongside Directors of Ideation and Brand Managers. Executed photography/videography, photo retouching and video editing. Directed day-to-day operations including project management, client meetings, pitching, estimating, bidding, price negotiation and bookkeeping.

• **Notable Clients:** L'Oréal, Maybelline, Diageo, Smirnoff, Tanqueray Gin, IW Harper, JUICE Pharma, Sterling Vineyards, Landor, Colangelo, Grind Espresso Spirit, Califresca, Blade & Bow, JWT and more.

MAKI HIROSE

Page Two of Two

Digital Imaging Specialist - Drive In Studios DI24 - New York, NY

2007-2012

Supervised and facilitated all digital imaging, photo retouching and digital asset management on Advertising Photoshoots. Designed, developed, coded using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Flash, updated, troubleshooted and maintained company and various clients' websites.

• **Notable Clients:** IBM, GE, Citibank, Microsoft, Sony, Vodafone, Merck & Co., Allianz, AstraZeneca, Ikea, Adidas Y-3, Kate Spade, Absolut Vodka, Six Flags, Macy's, Gillette, Food Network and more.

EDUCATION

New York University - New York, NY

2019-Present

UX Design for Emerging Technologies

Columbia University - New York, NY

2019

Full Stack Web Development

New York University - New York, NY

Bachelors of Fine Art in Photography & Imaging

New York University Honors Scholar and Founders' Day Award Recipient - Tisch School of the Arts

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) - Scrum Alliance - New York, NY

2019